Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Graphics, 1869-1940
  - Cap Merry und dunk Luftgriegelung venenter Parker 1 August 1883 3 1/2 Morgen, no. 8, Size: 8.5 x 16 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 8.5 x 16 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Cap Merry und dunk Luftgriegelung venannter Parker, 1 August 1883 3 1/2 Morgen, no. 14., Size: 10 x 16 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 10 x 16 cm., 14 x 19 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - View between two icebergs with small igloo, dog, sled, and person visible in foreground., 1883; Size: 11 x 13.5 cm., 13 x 18 cm. sheet., Format: 1 drawing; 11 x 13.5 cm., 13 x 18 cm. sheet.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Boas family, Size: 14 x 19.5 cm., 20 x 25 cm. sheet., Format: 1 photoprint; 14 x 19.5 cm., 20 x 25 cm. sheet.
  - Icebergs and ice, Size: 14 x 19 cm., Format: 1 drawing; 14 x 19 cm.; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Franz Boas, about age 12, school group portrait, ca. 1870; Size: 5.5 x 7b3 print on 9.5 x 11b3 mount, Format: 1 photoprint; 5.5 x 7b3 print on 9.5 x 11b3 mount
  - Altes Gymnasium, zu Minden i.W. (school of Franz Boas)., Size: 6.75 x 9b3 image on 8.5 x 10b3 paper, Format: 1 print; 6.75 x 9b3 image on 8.5 x 10b3 paper; Korber v. Freytag
  - Franz Boas. Bust, "quite ugly." From magazine feature on Epstein busts at London show. Reverse side has more interesting full-page Zenith radio advertisement., ca. 1937; Size: 10.25 x 12.25b3, Format: 1 print; 10.25 x 12.25b3
  - Jonas Meyer, 1853; Size: 6.75 x 7.5b3 print on 10.75 x 13.75b3 mount, Format: 1 lithograph; 6.75 x 7.5b3 print on 10.75 x 13.75b3 mount; Cajetan, L.
  - Henriette Menke Meyer., 1855; Size: 6.75 x 7.5b3 print on 10.75 x 13.75b3 mount, Format: 1 lithograph; 6.75 x 7.5b3 print on 10.75 x 13.75b3 mount; Cajetan, L.
  - Eisberg, 28th of Juli 1883., 1883 July 28
  - Franz Boas at banquet table with unidentified men, Mexico, 1912.
  - Franz Boas, about age four., ca. 1862; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Stucken, Ferd.
  - Franz Boas, about age four, standing next to railing, holding hat., ca. 1862; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Stucken, Ferd.
  - Franz Boas, about age eight, c.1., ca. 1866; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite
  - Franz Boas, about age eight, c.2., ca. 1866; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite
  - Franz Boas, age 10, 1868; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Franz Boas with Hete and Anne, ca. 1873; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Haack, Friedrich
  - Franz Boas as student, 1878-1879; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Laufs, Toni
  - Franz Boas as student, 1881; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Schmidt and Wegener
  - Franz Boas, "Franz as Freivillager", 1881-1882; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Franz Boas with Marie and Helene, reproduction, 1890, n.d.; Size: 4 x 5b3, Format: 1 photoprint; 4 x 5b3; Rice, F.H.
  - Wilhelm Werke (Boas' companion on Arctic expedition), ca. 1883; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 print; Carte de visite; Hering, Ernst
  - Wilhelm Werke, in Eskimo suit., 1883-1884; Size: Carte de visite, Format: 1 photoprint; Carte de visite; Sweers, M.
  - Die Germania am 20. August (news clipping of engraving). Notation on clipping: "in Kibberton Harbor", 1883; Size: 4 x 5b3, Format: 1 photoprint; 4 x 5b3
  - Die Station furz vor dem Berlaffen derfelben (news clipping of engraving). Notation on clipping: German Weather St---Cumberland Sound 1883.", Size: 4x5, Format: 1 print; 4x5
  - Boas, Franz, Oxford, England, 1912, Size: 4x5, Format: 1 photoprint; 4x5
  - Olden Times House 1: "Front end of the house finished to show the painting of killer whale and two true whales...", ca. 1920; Size: 4.25 x 3b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 4.25 x 3b3 print; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Olden Times House 2: "show the side of the house how the Boards held up by two poles tied together and the Roof according to seoset (?) story", ca. 1920; Size: 4.25 x 3b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 4.25 x 3b3 print; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Olden Times House 3: "side ways fram(e) of the house", ca. 1920; Size: 4.25 x 3b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 4.25 x 3b3 print; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - George Hunt family 1, with notations: "George Hunt, father-in-law of Dan Crammer as young man?" and "Probably Jonathan Hunt with father [Kathleen Mooney, May 1982]", ca. 1920; Size: 3 x 4b3 print in 3.5 x 5 cardboard mount, Format: 1 photoprint; 3 x 4b3 print in 3.5 x 5 cardboard mount; Chow, Yucho
  - George Hunt at Fort Rupert, B.C., ca. 1920; Size: 3.25 x 5b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 3.25 x 5b3 print
  - Kwakiutl girl, about age four, ca. 1920; Size: 3.5 x 4b3 print on card mount cut to size, Format: 1 photoprint; 3.5 x 4b3 print on card mount cut to size; Bishop, Giles
  - Boas, Franz, in front of home in Grantwood, New Jersey, ca. 1920; Size: 2.75 x 4.5b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 2.75 x 4.5b3 print
  - Boas, Franz in Albrechts, ca. 1929; Size: 2.75 x 4b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 2.75 x 4b3 print
  - Franz Boas, "Celebration in Bonn.", 1929; Size: 2.25 x 4.25b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 2.25 x 4.25b3 print
  - Franz Boas, "Bonn.", 1929; Size: 21/4 x 41/8b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 21/4 x 41/8b3 print
  - Franz Boas and Thomas Hunt Morgan "year when he was president American Association of Advancement of Science.", 1931; Size: 31/2 x 41/2b3 print, Format: 1 photoprint; 31/2 x 41/2b3 print
  - Franz Boas, at Cornwall Bridge, Conn., apparently late in life, seated in chair outdoors., ca. 1942; Size: 4x5, Format: 1 photoprint; 4x5
  - Franz Boas, portrait with buttoned jacket., 1884; Size: 4x5, Format: 1 photoprint; 4x5; Naegeli
  - Sophie Boas, seated, wearing full hoop skirt., 1888; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card
  - Franz Boas with wife Marie, c.1., 1887; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Naegeli
  - Franz Boas with wife Marie, c.2., 1887; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Naegeli
  - Franz Boas, with Marie and Helene, original print., 1890; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Rice, F.H.
  - Franz Boas with Gertrude, 3/4 view., ca. 1895; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Rockwood, J.R.
  - Franz Boas with Gertrude., ca. 1895; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Rockwood, J.R.
  - Minden Views 1: House of grandparents Boas (Caroline and Feihus Boas)., ca. 1890; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Minden Views 2: Rathaus, Minden i.W., ca. 1900; Size: 3.5 x 5b3, Format: 1 postcard; 3.5 x 5b3
  - Minden Views 3: Rathaus, Minden i.W., ca. 1900; Size: 4.5 x 6 print on 6.25 x 7.25b3 mount, Format: 1 photoprint; 4.5 x 6 print on 6.25 x 7.25b3 mount
  - Minden Views 4: Am Dom, Minden i.W., ca. 1900; Size: 4.5 x 6b3 print on 6.25 x 7.25b3 mount, Format: 1 postcard; 4.5 x 6b3 print on 6.25 x 7.25b3 mount
  - Franz Boas in Eskimo costume (standing), c. 1 (original, encased in Mylar)., 1883; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Franz Boas in Eskimo costume (standing), c.2., 1883; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Franz Boas in Eskimo costume (standing), c.3, reproduction., 1883; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Franz Boas, in Eskimo costume (seated), c. 1 (original)., 1883; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Franz Boas in Eskimo costume (seated), c. 2 (reproduction)., 1883; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Wilhelm Weike and wife Mathilde, c. 1 (original)., 1883; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Wenzel, Theodor
  - Kitterton (?) Harbor, Cumberland Sound., 1883-1884; Size: 4 1/4 x 6 1/2b3 print on cardboard mount, Format: 1 photoprint; 4 1/4 x 6 1/2b3 print on cardboard mount; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - On a trip in the Arctic., 1883-1884; Size: 4.25 x 6.5b3 print on cardboard mount, Format: 1 photoprint; 4.25 x 6.5b3 print on cardboard mount; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Franz Boas, portrait., 1887; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Bogardus, A.
  - Franz Boas, "World's Fair," 3/4 view portrait, c. 1., 1893; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Smith
  - Franz Boas, "World's Fair," 3/4 view portrait, c. 2 (missing lower right corner)., 1893; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Smith
  - Franz Boas, profile view: "Seinem lieben Wilhelm Weike zur freundlich Erinnung (?) Franz Boas Sommer 1901.", Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Fechner, Wilh.
  - Franz Boas, portrait, c. 1., 1912; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Gunther, Carl
  - Franz Boas, portrait, c. 2, 1912; Size: Cabinet card, Format: 1 photoprint; Cabinet card; Gunther, Carl
  - Kwakiutl man, woman, and girl., ca. 1920; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7; Bishop, Giles
  - George Hunt and family, c. 1., ca. 1930; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - George Hunt and family, c. 2 (missing corner top left; crease through center)., ca. 1930; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Kwakiutl Indians: Ceremonial masks., ca. 1930; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Kwakiutl Indians: Ceremonial masks and costumes., ca. 1930; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Franz Boas and three others, all in German military uniform., ca. 1881; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7; Hulsenbeck, J.
  - Franz Boas with gathering of anthropologists: Fay-Cooper Cole, Robert H. Lowie, A.C. Aitken, and Alexander A. Goldenweiser., ca. 1920; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Franz Boas with Leo Sternberg, "former member of council of State Prussia walking on street in Bogoras, Russia., ca. 1930; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Franz Boas, 70th birthday, Cornwall Bridge, seated in chair outdoors., 1928; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Franz Boas, 70th birthday, Cornwall Bridge, Conn., with Marie and grandchildren, outdoors (1)., 1928; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Franz Boas, 70th birthday, Cornwall Bridge, Conn., with Marie, children, and grandchildren, outdoors (2)., 1928; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Franz Boas, with grandsons Robert and Philip Yampolsky at Grantwood, N.J., ca. 1940; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Summer home at Bolton, Lake George, New York. (2)., ca. 1920; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Summer home at Bolton, Lake George, New York. (3) Small outbuilding, "Boas' study.", ca. 1920; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7
  - Marie Boas, about age 40, seated, 3/4 view., ca. 1900; Size: 5x7, Format: 1 photoprint; 5x7; Fechner, Wilh.
  - Eisberg, 28 Juli 1883, Size: 5x7, Format:; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Fjord von Kekurtalunkdjuaki, 1883; Size: 5x7, Format:; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Nenelung, Angiukak von Karsakgischen. NNW, Angiukak, 1400 meter., 1184; Size: 5x7, Format:; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Eingang zu Pagnirtung, Cumberland Sund., ca. 1883; Size: 5x7, Format:; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Ursualtlung (American Harbor) von SW gischen., ca. 1883; Size: 5x7, Format:; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Cape Searle (Kachodluin) von S. gischen (Katingujang and Nuvukshin), ca. 1883; Size: 5x7, Format:; 5x7; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
  - Map of Baffinland, ca. 1884; 1 map, 71.6 x 95.25 cm [irregular]; Size: 71.6 x 95.25 cm [irregular], Format:; 1 map; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
    Other Finding Aids note
    Realms of Gold, 6 (6).
  - Photographs
    - photographs, #1; 3--1 1/2 x 2 1/2 inch; 1--3 1/2 x 4 inch; Black and white photographs of pure albino Hawaiians
    - photographs, 1940; #2; Black and white photographs by Amelia Susman and William Beynon of Tsimshian sculptures, carvings, and totems, Port Simpson, British Columbia.; Susman, Amelia L.
      Beynon, William, 1888-1958
      - Gnawing beaver totem, 1940
- Microfilm
  - Reel 1, 1878 February 24-1889 January 31; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 2, 1889 February 1 - 1894 April 30; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 3, 1894 May 1 - 1898 December 30; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 4, 1899 January 5 - 1903 March 26; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 5, 1903 April 2 - 1904 December 30; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 6, 1905 January 2 - 1906 January 24; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 7, 1906 January 24 - 1907 January 4; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 8, 1907 January 4 - 1907 December 10; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 9, 1907 December 11 - 1908 December 4; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 10, 1908 December 5 - 1909 November 30; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 11, 1909 December 9 - 1911 February 17; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 12, 1911 February 17 - 1912 September 12; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 13, 1912 September 13 - 1913 June 14; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 14, 1913 June 11 - 1914 February 20; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 15, 1914 February 20 - 1915 April 16; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 16, 1915 April 16 - 1916 October 15; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 17, 1916 October 16 - 1917 May 31; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 18, 1917 June 1 - 1918 March 31; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 19, 1918 April 1 - 1919 April 2; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 20, 1919 April 3 - 1920 February 19; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 21, 1920 February 19 - 1920 July 31; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 22, 1920 August 1 - 1920 July 31; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 23, 1920 November 26 - 1922 December 29; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 24, 1923 Juanuary 9 - 1924 February 29; 1.0 Reel(s)
  - Reel 25
  - Reel 26
  - Reel 27
  - Reel 28
  - Reel 29
  - Reel 30
  - Reel 31
  - Reel 32
  - Reel 33
  - Reel 34
  - Reel 35
  - Reel 36
  - Reel 37
  - Reel 38
  - Reel 39
  - Reel 40
  - Reel 41
  - Reel 42
  - Reel 43
  - Reel 44
  - Reel 45
  - Reel 46